[ Watch on KissFlix.co ]
=Against The Current=
(Adapted from He Yanshan's novel, Orchid Fragrance Fate)
=Episode 29= (This drama does not correspond)
(to any real historical dynasty.)
(The systems, culture, attire and other dynastic elements have been adapted.)
(Glorify the Family Name)
Mother only said that to comfort Madam Wu.
She didn't mean any of it.
Don't take it to heart.
All right.
You're being awfully agreeable.
Is it because we're visiting your family today?
I cannot stay by my parents' side
and fulfill my duty to them.
I don't want them worrying about me anymore.
No matter how things are for me here,
in front of my parents,
I'll always say I'm doing well.
I hope you'll help me keep up appearances.
And I'll return the favor
by respecting your parents
and never putting you in a difficult position.
Don't worry.
I won't disappoint your parents.
Actually,
if you really want to put your parents' minds at ease,
come to the capital with me.
Then you'll be the madam of the household.
How you live your life
will be entirely up to you.
You should go on your own.
I'll stay in Jinling
and fulfill your filial duties in your stead.
(Glorify the Family Name)
Are you cold, Young Master?
No.
Bring me the cloak.
No need.
Those of us trained in martial arts aren't afraid of the cold.
Now that you mention it,
I am feeling a little cold.
If Mother sees
me wearing the cloak she made
when we visit her together,
she must think we newlyweds
are very happy together.
We're hardly a young newlywed couple at our age.
How can you even say that?
What are you laughing at?
Move.
I pay my respects to you, Mother.
Come inside.
Come in and sit down.
You're here. Come.
Mother.
Come.
Here, first,
have some hot tea.
Warm yourself up.
I'm not cold at all.
I'm wearing the cloak you made for me.
It's very warm.
Look. My palms are even sweating.
Come, sit down.
Sit.
Mother, are you stewing chicken?
Our home isn't very big,
so the kitchen is close by.
Is the smell too...
It smells wonderful.
I clearly ate my fill this morning,
but now
the aroma of chicken soup
and the sight of these fried dough twists
have made me hungry again.
If you don't mind,
I'd love a bowl of chicken soup
with some fried dough twists.
Wait here.
You're young, so of course you have a good appetite.
You're family. Make yourself at home.
Father is right.
I am young.
You're still young.
Here, Jinqi.
Try some.
Sure.
Thank you, Mother.
The soup is savory, and the fried dough twists are fragrant. Delicious.
They say one shouldn't talk while eating or sleeping.
I thought Young Master...
I thought you weren't allowed
to talk while eating.
We're not that particular.
Back in the military camp,
we'd even eat while arguing.
Mother, look.
Lanxiang keeps staring at me without saying a word.
She must think I'm eating too much.
I don't mind how much he eats.
Watching him enjoy it
just made me want some fried dough twists, too.
If you want some, just say so.
It's not like I'd deprive you.
Come.
Here.
Have you been busy with official duties?
I've already completed the handover.
I'm not busy at all.
Father, Mother,
there's something
I need to tell you both.
His Majesty has ordered me to take up a post in the capital.
It was all very sudden.
I have to leave tomorrow.
I want
to take Lanxiang with me.
I see.
This is such an important matter.
Why didn't you send someone back to tell us?
We could've prepared
some things for you in advance.
He's going. I'm not.
That's why we didn't tell you.
Lanxiang is mainly worried about the two of you.
But once I leave,
I'm afraid I won't be back for two or three years.
I wouldn't feel at ease leaving Lanxiang alone at the residence.
So I can only ask
that you let Lanxiang come to the capital with me.
Jinqi has a point.
You've only just gotten married.
You can't be apart for so long.
Your mother and I are in good health.
You don't need to worry about us.
Yes.
Now that Jinqi is going to the capital to take up a post,
you should go with him.
I nearly died from illness in the capital.
I don't want to go.
Lanxiang has been frail since childhood.
In the capital,
she nearly... nearly died from illness.
It frightened her.
How about this?
You...
You go on ahead.
In a few days,
when Lanxiang comes around,
she can join you there.
There'll still be time.
Mother, the chicken soup has gone cold.
I'll go get another hot bowl.
Sit down.
It's fine. I'll get it myself.
Just sit down.
No. You two...
Give it to me. Come on.
- Sit down. - Sit.
Thank you, Mother.
Father, please sit.
All right.
Finest quality fabric!
Sachets! Come take a look at our sachets!
Come take a look at our sachets!
(Lu Family Painting and Calligraphy Shop)
Sachets!
Take care!
One book bag and one pencil case.
Sure.
Jiugao, come help.
That'll be 1.6 coins.
Jiugao, wrap these up.
Why is business suddenly so good?
Could it be because His Majesty granted the marriage
and they're here to see what all the fuss is about?
Who would spend real money
just to see what all the fuss is about?
Scholar Han
lives next door.
Now,
word has spread that the pencil case and book bag Scholar Han uses
came from the shop.
So people come to share his good fortune,
and that they'll pass the examination next year too.
So the top provincial graduate actually lives next door.
What a stroke of luck.
There's no stopping it.
Shopkeeper.
How much is all this?
Let me see.
The books...
and this.
That'll be 7.1 coins altogether.
All right.
Here.
Thank you for your business.
Thank you.
Take care.
How many sachets?
Three.
What are you doing?
If you put another bug on my head,
I'm really going to hit you this time.
I'm not a child anymore.
Can you stop treating me like one?
They're silk flowers.
I saw them while I was out shopping.
They said they were from the capital,
so I bought two on a whim.
This is clearly Jinling silk.
You may have been fooled,
but they still look nice.
I'll keep one
and give the other to Yinchen.
These new items need to be sorted, right?
You've walked past here three times already.
This isn't a shop you should be eyeing.
Let go of me!
Please, let go of me!
It's you?
Zhi.
It really is you.
You...
Father.
For this visit,
Lanxiang and I also prepared
a gift for Mister Lu.
I'd like to pay him a visit, too.
I'll take you there.
All right.
Don't be afraid, child.
Don't be afraid.
Didn't you go home?
How did you end up like this?
What happened?
Say something.
Mother,
go get her a bowl of chicken soup.
I'll take Zhi inside for some food first.
Once she's feeling better,
we can catch up slowly.
Let's go inside. Come.
Sit down.
Here's the chicken soup.
Eat something first.
Have it while it's hot.
I'll heat some water.
You can wash up later.
You've been hungry for so long.
Have something soft first to warm your stomach.
Once you're feeling better,
I'll give you some meat.
My parents thought I was a disgrace.
They said
I never should've gone back.
I should've died out there.
They sold me to a cripple
in exchange for a calf.
I couldn't endure the abuse,
so I ran away.
But
I don't seem to know where else to go.
I kept walking
and walking
until my shoes wore through,
but I still didn't know where to go.
Eat.
Once you've had your fill and regained your strength,
we'll look for somewhere together.
The world is so vast.
We'll find you a place
one way or another.
Drink up.
Are you still looking for Ji'er?
Mister Lu and Furong are helping, too,
but there's been no news.
Still,
performers travel far and wide with their shows.
We'll hear something eventually.
I know where Ji'er is.
On my way here,
I saw that branded mule.
So while I was begging for leftovers,
I went closer and listened carefully.
What did you hear?
They do business in the capital.
Ji'er is in the capital.
Will you go to the capital to find Ji'er?
Of course.
I'll leave for the capital first thing tomorrow morning.
Tomorrow morning?
Here.
My son-in-law is going to the capital to take up his post.
It's been decided that he'll leave tomorrow.
Lanxiang didn't want to go at first,
but now it seems
she has no choice but to go.
Come in and test the water.
You have chilblains,
so I didn't make the water too hot.
Take it slowly.
♪Whose voice is still singing?♪
Is this all right?
♪A faint melody drifts through my dreams♪
♪A cold soul crosses the river, gazing toward the loyal family afar♪
♪As if destined by fate♪
♪To reunite, then wander once more♪
Zhi.
Tomorrow, we'll go to the capital together.
We'll find Ji'er together.
All right.
♪Promises are like candlelight, flickering in the wind♪
♪I watch the passing years wear away♪
♪Even deep affection slowly fades♪
♪The past falls like withered leaves♪
♪Scattered into the dust♪
Young Master.
These are sachets from the Lu Family Painting and Calligraphy Shop,
along with pencil cases and book bags.
Why are you giving me these?
This year's top provincial graduate
lives next door to the shop.
Many scholars have gone there to buy them,
saying they'll share in his good fortune
and pass the examination next year.
I was thinking
you could send these to Pengjian Study
in Young Madam's name.
Third Young Master and Fourth Young Master are studying now,
so they might share in his good fortune, too.
If they pass the examination one day,
Second Madam may remember Young Madam's kindness.
The top provincial graduate?
Scholar Han?
What did I do wrong?
Please tell me, Young Master.
You certainly know how to win people over for Young Madam.
You're leaving for the capital tomorrow.
Young Madam will be alone at the residence
with no one to rely on.
Naturally, it's best to win over whoever you can.
Since you're so devoted to her,
take these to Aunt Lingxiao.
Tell her
Young Madam and I
are giving them to Jinqiao and Jincen.
Mention you, too?
Yes.
You can go if you want.
I'm not going to the capital anyway.
You should go on your own.
I'll stay in Jinling
and fulfill your filial duties in your stead.
I'm not going.
I don't want to go.
I'm leaving for the capital tomorrow.
Knowing we won't see each other for a long time,
I can't help feeling a little down.
Would you mind having a drink with me?
Actually,
the capital is quite nice.
It's right under the Emperor's watch,
and blessed with outstanding people and places.
No matter how nice it is,
you still don't like it.
People
can change their minds
over time.
If you don't like it, so be it.
I don't want to force you.
Now that the transfer order has been issued,
I have no choice but to report for duty in the capital.
But I promise you
I'll petition His Majesty as soon as possible
to transfer me back to Jinling.
I'll drink first.
This rice liquor tastes a little strange.
Actually,
what I wanted to tell you is...
Lin Jinqi, you...
drugged me.
♪Look at us♪
♪We've shared countless beautiful moments♪
From now on,
you must never drink carelessly when you're out.
I did promise you
I'd get transferred back to Jinling as soon as possible.
But I never promised
to leave you behind in Jinling.
♪However deep the joy or sorrow♪
♪There will always be someone to share it with♪
♪Our bond runs deep♪
Lanxiang.
Now that you've married me,
stop thinking about Han Liang.
The past cannot be undone,
but the future is still ours to shape.
Whether he's Provincial Examination Top Scholar Han
or Top Imperial Scholar Han,
he has nothing to do with us.
Young Master, Old Master sent word
that he wishes to see you.
He's already waiting for you in the ancestral hall.
Grandfather.
Grandfather,
you summoned me here.
What guidance do you have for me?
Do you know
I'm not pleased that you're going to the capital?
I had some sense of that.
I just don't know
the reason behind it.
This move to the capital
may seem like a promotion that brings honor to our family,
but fortune often conceals misfortune.
I'm afraid that one day,
the destruction of the Lin family
may begin with you.
Though I may be unworthy,
I've always kept your teachings and my mentor's in mind.
I've never done anything to disgrace our family.
Why would you say that, Grandfather?
The sages taught the Three Bonds and Five Constant Virtues.
Have you lived by them?
Marrying without telling you
was indeed my fault.
But...
I did inform His Majesty.
The father guides the son.
Today, when your father goes against your wishes,
you dare use the sovereign's authority against him.
The sovereign guides his subjects.
If one day the sovereign goes against your wishes,
what will you dare use against him then?
Grandfather, that's too grave an accusation.
I would never do that,
nor would I dare.
Observe what a man does.
Consider why he does it.
See where his heart finds peace.
How can he hide his true self?
Can you swear before our ancestors
that you've never deceived His Majesty or defied his authority?
What exactly did this man do
that forced him to leave his homeland and seek refuge overseas?
His clan was fighting over the family estate.
After his father lost the dispute,
he disappeared without a trace.
He no longer wanted to fight over it,
but his relatives didn't believe him.
They were determined to eliminate him.
(Afraid of implicating anyone else,)
(he had no choice but to flee far away.)
Grandfather.
I...
I don't want to know
what you've done,
and I hope I never
have to know.
Serving the Emperor is like living beside a tiger.
I agreed to let
Jinlan, Jinqiao, and Xiuwan
go to the capital
with you
because I want you to think of your siblings
before you act
and exercise some restraint.
They all deserve
to live well.
To live.
To live well.
Grandfather.
You agreed to let Jinlan come with us?
Jinqi, that's wonderful!
Thank you for granting my wish, Grandfather.
Did I pass your test, Jinqi?
You did.
Rest and recover, Jinqi.
I'll study hard.
I'll go make funny faces
for Aunt Shunhua.
Old Madam always laughs when I make funny faces.
You're awake, my lady.
I'm on the ship?
We've already
been away from Longjiang Pass Wharf for over four hours.
Where's Zhi?
The person you brought back
was naturally brought aboard with us.
Didn't she say anything?
Say what?
My lady.
Are you still dizzy?
Do you feel unwell anywhere?
My lady.
I was wrong.
It was my fault.
It took me so long to finally marry you.
I truly couldn't bear to be apart from you for even one day.
I promise you
I'll petition His Majesty as soon as possible
to transfer me back to Jinling.
My lady.
I know
what I did this time was far too reckless.
I'll accept any punishment you give me.
As long as it helps you calm down.
If you're angry,
just let it out.
Hit me or scold me.
Don't keep it bottled up inside.
It's not good for your health.
You actually drugged me with a knockout drug.
Even a play wouldn't dare make up something this outrageous.
Even if I wrote it, no one would believe it.
It wasn't a knockout drug.
Well, it wasn't a knockout drug.
I got a physician to prescribe something to help you sleep.
It won't harm you.
But I clearly saw you drink it, too.
I pretended.
It looked like I drank it, but actually
I poured it onto the
handkerchief in my sleeve.
Now that would make a good scene in a play.
So are you angry or not?
Guess.
Then you've forgiven me?
I'll reserve judgment and see how you behave.
How I behave?
Look at that miserable face of yours.
Let me teach you a few tricks.
You've got to be completely shameless.
Then things will work out for you.
Stop giving me bad advice.
I've got five children already.
You know about fighting.
But women?
That's my specialty.
Persistence always wins a woman over.
The ship is only so big.
You're bound
to keep running into each other.
Get seasick, and she might fall right into your arms.
And when you bathe, you'll have to undress, won't you?
(Your wife is young.)
(I guarantee)
(she'll get all flustered and start blushing.)
I... undress.
I want to take a bath.
=Against the Current= (Next Episode's Preview)
Open your eyes and take a good look!
It's your man who's been pestering me all day.
You can't control your own man, so you take your anger out on me.
If you've got the nerve, go hit your man.
Go on, hit him!
Why are they fighting again?
You...
♪Spring slips from the branches once more♪
♪Flowers bloom unseen, as they have before♪
♪All the joys and sorrows come and go♪
♪While loss leaves winter in the heart♪
♪Though all the world may fade♪
♪Time rolls on as countless lives rush by♪
♪Night winds wander through the halls of long ago♪
♪No page could hold the longing words can never show♪
♪Every joy and sorrow in this fleeting life♪
♪Fades into the past as new wounds rise♪
♪While whispers of perfume linger beneath the eaves♪
♪Let the cold wind rage, let the wild rain fall♪
♪Let sorrow spill like shadows over all♪
♪Let love fall to pieces, let old anger burn away♪
♪Let the past die with yesterday♪
♪One last fire, one last cup of wine♪
♪And silver moonlight to guide me through the night♪
♪Let beginnings fade as endings come to call♪
♪From this endless dream, there's no return at all♪
♪Let the cold wind rage, let the wild rain fall♪
♪Let sorrow spill like shadows over all♪
♪Let love fall to pieces, let old anger burn away♪
♪Let the past die with yesterday♪
♪One last fire, one last cup of wine♪
♪And silver moonlight to guide me through the night♪
♪Let beginnings fade as endings come to call♪
♪From this endless dream, there's no return at all♪